Guide to the Japanese American Social Services, Inc. (JASSI) TAM.357
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Japanese American Social Services, Inc. (JASSI) Records
1981-2005
TAM.357
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
22.0 linear feet 22 boxes
The Japanese American Social Services, Inc. (JASSI) was formed in 1981 by Midori Shimanouchi Lederer to address the lack of social services for aging Japanese Americans with limited English language skills and little access to information about social service programs. Currently the only professional social services agency for the Japanese community on the East Coast, it provides information or referral services to a wide range of Japanese Americans, including restaurant workers, students, recent immigrants, and and others in the New York area. This unprocessed collection contains administrative materials, including minutes, correspondence, grant applications and employee files as well as financial information such as budgets, audits and payroll information. Also included are materials on services, workshops and events sponsored by JASSI, including client files, intake sheets and volunteer work records. Publicity materials, including brochures, newsletters and press releases are also present. The collection also includes photographs and scrapbooks documenting JASSI events and services.
Japanese American Social Services, Inc.
Box 1-22
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Japanese American Social Services, Inc. (JASSI) sent a gift of their records in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.028.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Japanese American Social Services, Inc. (JASSI) was formed in 1981 by Midori Shimanouchi Lederer to address the lack of social services for aging Japanese Americans with limited English language skills and little access to information about social service programs. Starting with a staff of three workers, JASSI quickly grew to encompass assistance for a broad range of needs, including legal and immigration issues and family problems, expanding beyond just elder Japanese Americans. Currently the only professional social services agency for the Japanese community on the East Coast, the organization provides information or referral services to a wide range of Japanese Americans, including restaurant workers, students, recent immigrants, and those in need of counseling or other referral services in the New York area.
Sources: Japanese American Social Services, Inc. “About JASSI.” http://www.jassi.org/index.html.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains administrative materials, including minutes, correspondence, grant applications and employee files as well as financial information such as budgets, audits and payroll information. Also included are materials on services, workshops and events sponsored by JASSI, including client files, intake sheets and volunteer work records. Publicity materials, including brochures, newsletters and press releases are also present. The collection also includes photographs and scrapbooks documenting JASSI events and services.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions, but with the following provisons:
NOTE: In order to protect the privacy of individual clients and/or employees, researchers who are granted access to case files must, before viewing these files, sign the Library's Case Files Policy Form, by which they agree that in their writings and public presentations they will not refer to individuals by name, or describe them in any way that will compromise their privacy or that of their families. When researchers use the information in these case files they agree to describe clients and employees as sociological aggregates, never as individuals.
Japanese American Social Services, Inc.; Japanese American Social Services, Inc.; Japanese Americans |x Economic conditions; Japanese Americans |x Legal status, laws, etc.; Japanese Americans |x Services for |z New York (State) |Z New York.; Japanese Americans |x Social conditions.; Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.; Older people |z New York (State) |z New York |x Social conditions.; Older people |z New York (State) |z New York.
- JASSI newsletters; Bylaws; JASSI Reports (Newsletter); Fundraising letter (1990-2002); JASSI history; Mine Okubo Trust Fund; Tokiko Kato; 1982-2002 (Box 1)
- Health brochures; Articles on Japanese Americans; Pacific Citizen newsletter; Articles about health/healthcare with annotations; Board meeting notes (2002-2003); JASSI staff CVs and notes; Press Releases (1994-2000); Montly Events (2002-2005); Correspondence (1990-1994); AALDEF Newsletter Outlook (1989-2000); 1989-2005 (Box 2)
- Board meeting minutes (1989-2000); Budget (1987-1995); Kazu Matsui of the Mets event (2001-2003); 2005 JASSI Gala; Business cards; Board member profiles (2003); Newsletter (2004-2005); 1989-2005 (Box 3)
- Department for the Aging financial materials, 1995-2000 (Box 4)
- Grant applications (2003-2004); Board evaluations; 2002 Technology Infrastructure grant (correspondence, application); Donations (2003-2004); Buddhist Churches of America (correspondence regarding donations) (1992-2003); 1999-2005 grant proposals, 1992-2005 (Box 5)
- Insurance (2003-2004); Income Taxes form 990 (1995-2005); Financial Statements (1999-2000, 2000-2001) Board Meeting minutes; Donation letters (1989-2003); Donations from Yoko Ono (2003) and Furumoto Realty, 1989-2005 (Box 6)
- Employee files, 2000-2004 (Box 7)
- Client files, 1997-2005 (Box 8)
- Intake files relating to clients recovering from 9/11; Other workshops held by JASSI, 1995-2004 (Box 9)
- JASSI Senior Program Events 2004 Vol. 1:Jan-June Guide to Immigration Counseling by the Center for Immigration Rights (July 1985); Helping People in your Community Understand Basic Financial Services by the Financial Services Education Coalition; New York Medicare Roster of participating physicians & providers (2002); Various brochures relating: including ones related to child health, diabetes, high blood pressure; Managed Care Presentation Training Guide; Caring for Your NonProfit, 1985-2004 (Box 10)
- Senior Program Event Vol. 2: July 2004-Dec 2004; Monthly Senior Event 2001; Monthly Senior Event 2002; Monthly Senior Event 2003; JASSI Senior intake forms 1999 Vol. 2: April-July 1999-2004 (Box 11)
- JASSI Senior intake forms 1999 Vol. 3; JASSI Senior intake forms 2000 Jan-Mar; JASSI Senior intake forms 2000 April 1999-2000 (Box 12)
- JASSI Senior intake forms 2001 Vol. 1: Jan; JASSI Senior intake forms 2001 Vol. 2: May; JASSI Senior intake forms 2001 Vol. 3: Oct; JASSI Senior intake forms 2002 Vol. 1: Jan-May 2001-2002 (Box 13)
- JASSI Senior intake forms 2002 Vol. 2: Jun-Dec; JASSI Senior intake forms 2003 Vol. 1: Jan; JASSI Senior intake forms 2003 Vol. 2: Aug; JASSI Senior intake forms 2004, 2002-2004 (Box 14)
- JASSI Senior Citizen Emergency Contact Sheet (2000-2004); Volunteer Work Logs (1999); Volunteer Work Logs (2000); Other volunteer files (1996-2002); Retired volunteers (2002-2003), 1996-2003 (Box 15)
- Volunteer Work Logs (2001); Volunteer Work Logs (2002); Volunteer Work Logs (2003); Volunteer Work Logs (2004), 2001-2004 (Box 16)
- 3-ring binder photo albums with newspaper clippings about JASSI (in English and Japanese); 82 Jan – 83 May; 83 Jan- 86 Feb; 86 Sep-89 June; 89 Dec-92 May, 1982-1992 (Box 17)
- 3-ring binder photo albums with newspaper clippings about JASSI (in English and Japanese); 92 May-94 Dec; 94 Oct -98 Aug, 1992-1998 (Box 18)
- Photo album, Photographs, 1982-1990 (Box 19)
- Photographs, 1991-1999 (Box 20)
- Photographs, 2000-2003 (Box 21)
- Books and artifacts; Japanese Hanja dictionary; Japanese-English dictionary; Lone Heart Mountain by Estelle Ishigo; Report of the 1993 Japan Study Program for Asian Social Service Workers; Social Welfare Services in Japan (Revised edition 1990); Health and Welfare in Japan by the Ministry of Health and Welfare; Overview of Social Welfare Services in Japan in 1994 by Japanese National Council of Social Welfare; Social Welfare in Tokyo (1993) by Tokyo Metropolitan Government; Japan-US Community Worker Exchange Program Report; Outline of Social Insurance in Japan (1981) by the Social Insurance Agency of the Japanese Government, 1981-1994, undated (Box 22)